# Dr. Changjiang Cai

Staff Research Engineer in 3D Vision - InnoPeak Technology, Inc

 $\Box$  +1 (201) 912-1947

☐ changjiangcai2020@gmail.com(primary), ccai1@stevens.edu
☑ www.changjiangcai.com
• in changjiang-cai
• ☐ ccj5351

### **About**

I am serving as a Sr. researcher in 3D computer vision with InnoPeak Technology, Inc., to solve problems in 3D reconstruction and XR(AR/VR/MR) via leveraging my knowledge of Computer Vision and Machine Learning. I obtained my Ph.D. degree of Computer Science from *Stevens Institute of Technology*. My research interests focus on image and video based 3D reconstruction, human mesh recovery and representation learning.

#### **Education**

#### **Stevens Institute of Technology**

Hoboken, New Jersey, USA

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science, in May 2021

Research Interests: Computer Vision and Machine Learning. Specifically, Stereo Vision, Depth Prediction, 3D reconstruction and Human Mesh Recovery.

Advisor: Philippos Mordohai (https://mordohai.github.io)

#### **Stevens Institute of Technology**

Hoboken, New Jersey, USA

 $^{\circ}$  Master of Engineering in Electrical Engineering, in February 2016

Concentration: Computer Vision and Machine Learning.

Advisor: Gang Hua (http://www.ganghua.org)

#### Xi'an Jiaotong University

Xi'an, Shaanxi, China

Mechanical Engineering

Research Area: Digital Image Processing. Advisor: Dehong Yu

#### Northwestern Polytechnical University

Xi'an, Shaanxi, China

B.E. in Automobile Engineering, in July 2009

Thesis: Structural Design and 3D Modeling of an Assistive Robot. Advisor: Renping Shao

### **Publications**

#### Published...

- o Jiachen Liu, Pan Ji, Nitin Bansal, **Changjiang Cai**, Qingan Yan, Xiaolei Huang, Yi Xu. *PlaneMVS: 3D Plane Reconstruction from Multi-View Stere*. In CVPR 2022, New Orleans, LA, June 2022.
- **Changjiang Cai**, Philippos Mordohai. *Do End-to-end Stereo Algorithms Under-utilize Information?* In International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV), 2020.

- Changjiang Cai, Matteo Poggi, Stefano Mattoccia, and Philippos Mordohai, Matchingspace Stereo Networks for Cross-domain Generalization. In International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV), 2020.
- o Konstantinos Batsos, **Changjiang Cai**, Philippos Mordohai. *CBMV: A coalesced bidirectional matching volume for disparity estimation*. In CVPR 2018, Salt Lake City, Utah, June 2018.
- o **Changjiang Cai**, Haipei Sun, Boxiang Dong, Bo Zhang, Ting Wang, Hui Wang. *Pairwise Ranking Aggregation by Non-interactive Crowdsourcing with Budget Constraints*. The 37th IEEE International Conference on Distributed Computing (ICDCS), June, 2017, Atlanta, GA.
- Haoxiang Li, Mohammed Kutbi, Xin Li, Changjiang Cai, Philippos Mordohai, Gang Hua, An Egocentric Computer Vision based Co-Robot Wheelchair. IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2016.

#### Preprints/Submissions.....

o Ren Li, **Changjiang Cai**, Georgios Georgakis, Srikrishna Karanam, Terrence Chen, Ziyan Wu. *Towards Robust RGB-D Human Mesh Recovery*. arXiv:1911.07383.

### **Projects**

- o **2022 Project** Consistent Dense Depth Estimation from Multi-view Stereo or Monocular Videos
  - Reconstructing geometrically consistent depth for dense pixels in multi-view stereo images or a monocular video via leveraging structure-from-motion to establish geometric constraints among common pixels shared by many views.
- **2021 Project** GCN based Local Expansion for End-to-end MRF Energy Optimization
  - Integrating local  $\alpha$ -expansion to GCN for end-to-end solution of MRF energy optimization (e.g., in stereo matching, semantic segmentation and optical flow estimation).
- o **2020 Project** Self-/Un-supervised Robust Presentation Learning
  - Self- or un-supervised learning for a robust representation which aims to improve semantic segmentation, optical flow estimation and monocular or stereo depth estimation.
- **2020 Project** Do End-to-end Stereo Algorithms Under-utilize Information?
  - Incorporated content-adaptive deep filtering techniques into SOTA networks (including DispNetC, GCNet, PSMNet, and GANet) for improved stereo matching.
- **2019 Project** Matching-space Stereo Networks for Cross-domain Generalization
  - Proposed a novel family of architectures with domain-invariant generalization.
- o **2019 Project** Depth-Aware Human Mesh Recovery
  - Proposed a new method using RGB-D data to estimate a parametric human mesh model
- o **2018 Project** CBMV\_ROB Entry in the Robust Vision Challenge, CVPR'18 workshop
  - Submitted the CBMV\_ROB entry in the stereo challenge, leveraging CBMV volume as in our previous work and local expansion algorithm for optimization.
- o **2017 Project** CBMV: A Coalesced Bidirectional Matching Volume for Disparity Estimation
  - Generated a matching volume by coalescing diverse evidence from a bidirectional matching process via random forest classifiers.
- 2016 Project Crowdsourcing: Budget-conscious Ranking by Non-interactive Crowdsourcing
  - Designed a crowdsourced ranking algorithm enabling task requester to obtain a good

full ranking result from the crowdsourced pairwise comparison, with a limited budget.

• 2015 Project Epitome Transform Coding: Towards Joint Compression of Images

Proposed epitome transform coding, an approach to joint compression of a set of images.

## **Industry Experience**

Full-time

Staff Research Scientist

Full-time

Sr. Research Scientist

Part-time intern

Research Intern

Summer intern

Research Intern

Summer intern

ີ Research Intern

InnoPeak Technology, Inc. Palo Alto, CA

Nov 2022 – Present

InnoPeak Technology, Inc. Palo Alto, CA

Jun 2021 – Nov 2022

Futurewei Technologies, Inc. Seattle, WA

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

Futurewei Technologies, Inc. Seattle, WA

*May* 2020 – *Aug* 2020

UII America, Cambridge, MA

*May* 2019 – *Aug* 2019

# **Teaching Experience**

CS442 - Database Management Systems

Teaching Assistant

**Stevens Institute of Technology** *Aug* 2016 – *Dec* 2016

### **Services**

- Reviewer for the following journals:
  - IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP)
  - IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM)
  - International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)
- Reviewer for the following conferences:
  - ACM Multimedia Conference (Since ACMMM 2020)
  - AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (Since AAAI 2022)
  - International Conference on Pattern Recognition (Since ICPR 2022)
  - International Conference on Multimedia Information Processing and Retrieval (MIPR'22)
  - IEEE/CVF Conf. on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (Since CVPR 2023)

### **Skills**

- **Programming Languages:** Python, C/C++, CUDA, Python& C++ Hybrid, MATLAB
- Deep Learning: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Caffe
- o Machine Learning: Numpy, Scikit-learn, Scipy, Pandas
- Computer Vision and 3D Geometry: OpenCV, PyTorch Geometric, TensorFlow Graphics
- Other Library & APIs: Matplotlib, Cython, Boost C++

- o Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL
- o Tools: Vim, Git, CMake, Bash, Tmux, Visual Studio Code, MeshLab, Office, Latex
- o OS Platforms: Linux, macOS, Windows

# Languages

o Chinese (native), English (proficient)

# Hobbies

- o Playing Basketball, Running and Biking
- o Driving and Road Trip